civilbeat.com 2017-06-06

# Civil Beat Privacy Policy - Honolulu Civil Beat

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information that you may provide through the Civil Beat service. This policy tells you how we use and protect your personal information on http://www.civilbeat.org. Except for information we collect about you from our payment platforms, this privacy policy only applies to information we collect through our website and does not apply to information collected from other sources. This policy is effective as of June 1, 2016. The Civil Beat service is owned and operated by Honolulu Civil Beat Inc. so you are agreeing to the terms in this agreement with Honolulu Civil Beat Inc.

We will keep this privacy policy posted on our website and encourage you to read and understand it. We take your privacy seriously and think you probably do as well. We may change our privacy policy from time to time by posting the changes on our website. So please review this privacy policy frequently to make sure you’re informed about our current privacy policy. When you access and use our website, you’re agreeing to the terms in this privacy policy (as well as our terms of service). If you do not agree to the terms in the privacy policy or terms of service, please do not use our service.

### Information We Collect

No Information Required. There may be limited parts of our website that you may use without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself.

Information We Collect Upon Membership Registration.When you donate to us or authorize us to collect payment via our payment platforms, we create your Civil Beat membership account. For members that signed up using PayPal, we do receive some information about you (which is governed by the PayPal user agreement that you have with PayPal). We may also ask you to provide additional information from time-to-time.

PayPal Password. Please note that we do not collect or have access to your PayPal password. Your PayPal password is between PayPal and you., We use PayPal to authenticate you but that authentication is done though PayPal’s website and servers. We will not ask you to share your PayPal password with us.

Optional Information. You may have the opportunity to provide us with additional, optional information about yourself. You may choose to do this because it enhances the Civil Beat experience for you and/or other Civil Beat users. This may include a URL of your choosing, or some free-form text that you might want to include about yourself.

### Commenting

We also give anyone the ability to participate in discussions on the website through our commenting system Civil Comments. While we hope that you will consider being a constructive participant in these discussions, whether you decide to participate is entirely up to you. When you provide us this information, you agree and understand that this information may be made public to the entire world and that it is not entitled to the protections in this privacy policy. Optional information may also be combined with information from other users or third-parties. Other users may rate or comment about your optional information, and/or your information may be combined with Civil Beat content. If this isn’t agreeable to you, then please do not provide this optional information to us. We can’t control what the entire world does with this optional information and are not responsible for whatever happens to this optional information.

Log Data. We may record some or all of the information your browser sends to our servers. This may include information such as your IP address, the domain you are visiting from, your browser type, the third party website from which your visit originated, the operating system you are using, the pages you visit on our website, and/or terms you may have searched for. We use this information to monitor and improve the technical performance of our website and to improve the overall Civil Beat service.

### How We Use Your Information

General Use. Our primary purpose in collecting and using your personal information is to provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience. This might include helping us carry out your requests, respond to your inquiries, or just better serve you.

Communication. If you provide us your personal contact information on Civil Beat (e.g., email, phone number, Twitter username) we may use it to provide you Civil Beat functionality, market to you, and/or provide you information about the Civil Beat service. If you do not wish to receive such communication or information from us, please unsubscribe using the instructions provided in the communication. We may also send messages to your Twitter account just like any other user of the Twitter service.

Improving our Service. We may use personal information to better understand user behavior and research & analysis in order to operate and improve the Civil Beat service.

Aggregated Non-Personal Information. We may share aggregated non-personal information with third parties.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties without your explicit consent.

### Remarketing

We are using a third party technology to remarket our website/products based on your behaviour while using this site. Note that only non-personally identifiable information is used in this process. This means that depending which pages you visit on this website, your browser can become part of an audience, thus be exposed to our ads though third-party ad networks (including Google) across the Internet.

These third-party vendors (including Google) use cookies to serve ads based on your past visits to this website.

You can opt out of being included in remarketing by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

We are also using Doubleclick remarketing pixels, you can opt out of Doubleclick’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page or the DoubleClick opt-out page.

### How We Protect Your Information

We understand that you are trusting us with the personal information you share with us. We take this very seriously and treat your information as an asset that must be protected. Your information is stored on our servers located in the United States. We use tools (encryption, passwords, etc.) to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. However, despite our best efforts, there may be third parties that try to hack into our systems or intercept our data communications. Therefore, although we will work very hard to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee that your personal information or private communications will remain private 100% of the time.

### Cookies

In order to improve the Civil Beat service and your experience, we use “cookie” technology. A cookie is a small file placed on your hard drive that can be used to do things such as: help us better understand how people use our service, remember your settings when you repeatedly visit our website, and let you customize your Civil Beat experience. A few additional things you might want to know about cookies:

You can adjust your cookie settings in your browser (and may turn off cookies entirely). There are certain features that are only available through the use of cookies.

### Our Disclosure of Your Information

Despite anything else we’ve said in this policy, we may disclose your personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, or protect anyone’s rights, property or safety. If we do disclose your information for one of these reasons, we will do it in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

We may also share your personal information with:

Third party service providers necessary to provide the service (e.g., data hosting providers), in which case we require that they comply with our Privacy Policy and take appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Other third parties whom you explicitly ask us to send your information to  
Law enforcement or other government officials, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity. In such events, we will disclose information that is relevant to the investigation.

Other Sites / Links  
Our website may link or contain links to other third-party websites that we do not control or maintain. We are not responsible for the privacy policies employed by any third-party website. Anytime you leave our website and visit a third-party website, we encourage you to read and review the privacy policies and practices of those third-party websites before submitting any personal information.
